<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rpi on Jerome Brette&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/rpi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rpi on Jerome Brette&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rpi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and Deploy Kubernetes Hashicorp Vault</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-01-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-01-a/</guid>
      <description> Goal Vault is aiming at improving security of the containers by rotating token and credential much more often than usual. Looks like it is especially effectiv to help rotate passwords used to access internal databases.
Key Aspects  Compile and deploy the vault code in vault  Deploy  WIP  Conclusion  WIP  Reference Links  Official HashiCorp Code  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and Deploy Kubernetes Istio</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-31-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-31-a/</guid>
      <description> Goal Istio is aiming at improving security of the containers. One of the key aspects is the end to end encryption of the commnucation, the role of citadel to ensure the management of the certificates, the renewal of the certificates. As always, the goal of this post is to study that new tool and figure out I can leverage it in my day to day work.
Key Aspects  Compile and deploy the istio code in istio  Deploy  WIP  Conclusion  WIP  Reference Links  Official istio Code  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and Deploy Kubernetes test-infra</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-30-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-30-a/</guid>
      <description> Goal test-infra seems to somewhat overlap with sonobuoy features. The purpose of this post is to fetch the code, compile and deploy it on a Kubernetes cluster.
Key Aspects  Compile and deploy the test-infra code in test-infra  Deploy  WIP  Conclusion  WIP  Reference Links  Official test-infra Code  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and Deploy Kubernetes Kustomize</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-29-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-29-a/</guid>
      <description> Goal kustomize seems to help the setup of multiple clusters by removing copy paste accross cluster and still keeping the configuration file has plain yaml instead of the template like it is often the case with t
Key Aspects  Compile and deploy the Kustomize code in Kustomize  Deploy  WIP  Conclusion  WIP  Reference Links  Kustomize Description Official Kustomize Code  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build and Deploy MachineLearning Kubeflow Framework</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-19-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-19-a/</guid>
      <description> Goal Kubeflow is a process that allows you to deploy machine learning infrastructure on top of a Kubernetes cluster. The goal here is to deploy Kubeflow first on a local simple Kubernetes cluster running in a VM and then deploy it in the Kubernetes PI Cluster
Key Aspects  WIP  Deploy  WIP  Conclusion  WIP  Reference Links  [Kubernetes cross build]()  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZWave/ZigBee network and Linear HUSBZB‑1</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-06-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-06-a/</guid>
      <description>Goal In order to transforme a PI into a home automation controller, it is necessary to add Zwave and ZigBee capabilities to the the Wifi and Bluetooth capabilities of the PI.
Key  Transform Raspberry-PI + Dongle into a SUC ZWave controller Try to use with OpenHAB or HomeAssistant  Testing on the OpenHAB Container The OpenHAB architecture is Java based.
Testing on the HomeAssistant Container HomeAssistant is Python based and relies on OpenZWave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install OpenHAB on docker &#43; Raspberry PI3</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-05-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-05-a/</guid>
      <description>Goal OpenHAB running on Raspberry PI is one of way where you don&amp;rsquo;t have to rely on outside services to orchestrate your IOT. Then comes the issues of high availability of the software if only running on one PI. By dockerizing the software first, this open the doors to leverage a kubernetes cluster to ensure HA of the software
Key Aspects  Use the 3 nodes Raspeberry Cluster Access the WIFI, ZWave and Zigbee network Leverage the Nortek HUSBZB-1 Zwave and Zigbee dongle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install HomeAssistant on docker &#43; Raspberry PI3</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-04-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-04-a/</guid>
      <description>Goal HomeAssistant running on Raspberry PI is one of way where you don&amp;rsquo;t have to rely on outside services to orchestrate your IOT. Then comes the issues of high availability of the software if only running on one PI. By dockerizing the software first, this open the doors to leverage a kubernetes cluster to ensure HA of the software
Key Aspects  Use the 3 nodes Raspeberry Cluster Access the WIFI, ZWave and Zigbee network Leverage the Nortek HUSBZB-1 Zwave and Zigbee dongle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>