<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homeautomation on Jerome Brette&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/homeautomation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homeautomation on Jerome Brette&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/homeautomation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ZWave/ZigBee network and Linear HUSBZB‑1</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-06-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-06-a/</guid>
      <description>Goal  Transform Raspberry-PI + Dongle into a SUC ZWave controller Try to use with OpenHAB or HomeAssistant  Testing on the OpenHAB Container The OpenHAB architecture is Java based.
Testing on the HomeAssistant Container HomeAssistant is Python based and relies on OpenZWave. Some of the data is also saved in SQLite. In both cases developping small Python scripts to investigate the setup seems to be the easiest way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install OpenHAB on docker &#43; Raspberry PI3</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-05-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-05-a/</guid>
      <description>Goal  Use the 3 nodes Raspeberry Cluster Access the WIFI, ZWave and Zigbee network Leverage the Nortek HUSBZB-1 Zwave and Zigbee dongle. Try to install OpenHab on node 3 of the cluster (Picture to be update with Dongle on bottom node).  Setup the host operating system Moved the dongle to the third node of the cluster. Check it is present
~~~~ lsusb
Bus 001 Device 004: ID 10c4:8a2a Cygnal Integrated Products, Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install HomeAssistant on docker &#43; Raspberry PI3</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-04-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-04-a/</guid>
      <description>Goal  Use the 3 nodes Raspeberry Cluster Access the WIFI, ZWave and Zigbee network Leverage the Nortek HUSBZB-1 Zwave and Zigbee dongle. Install Home Assistant on node 2 of the cluster  What OS  Home Assistant haas.io does not support Raspberry 3 B+ yet. haas.io is based on ResinOS. ResinOS is not using docker anymore but balena which does not support kubernetes yet See Issue Continue to use HyperiotOS  Install AppArmor and download docker container cat newpgklist apparmor-utils apt-transport-https avahi-daemon ca-certificates curl dbus jq network-manager socat software-properties-common  for i in `cat newpgklist` do sudo apt-get install -y $i done  Download and run the installation script.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>